Pradeep Kumar Kushwaha



pradeepkushwahakumar@gmail.com



+917838310825



linkedin.com/in/prakumk



https://github.com/prakumk

Summary

B.Tech in CSE (Batch 2012-2016) | Passionate in Android and iOS development

A good problem solver and love to research on new way of solving problems. Always looking forward to Implement new ideas. Believe in leading from the front, always up to take initiatives. My Interests and hobbies constitute Web Development, Android Application Development for Handhelds and Wearables. Also a reliable Team Mate.

My Key Skills include:

- · Positive toward Problem Solving
- Good at analytics
- · Strategy Building for quick and efficient result
- Always looking forward to find optimal solution

Experience



Engineering Manager

Qandle

Apr 2018 - Present (3 years 9 months +)

Handling Android, IOS and React based frontend development by collaboration with API team to deliver product on time.

Worked on flask based auto-sales-lead assignment tool that fetches all incoming emails and by auto classification of mails assigns these leads to Qandle Sales Team. Apart from this admin has a dashboard to monitor all these and reassign.

Created Windows, Mac-OS and Linux desktop application for Qandle Remote Kit(Used to keep track of on what application their employees are spending time. It can also take screenshots at random intervals too if enabled by admin.)

Q

Android and IOS Developer

Qandle

Jun 2016 - Apr 2018 (1 year 11 months)

>> ANDROID and iOS Application Developer.<<

- Design and implement calendar to app that is same as google calendar.
- · GPS based Odometer to track user's distance.
- NLP to process user's data that can be used to add reminders by simply saying date and time or schedule a meeting.
- Smart scanning of bills for claim processing text mining is done to fetch important text from hard copy bills and submit data for approval by manager.
- Design Cool UI with cards view that supports left and right swipe to see cards details.

- JSON parsing with minimum line of code.
- Auto layout designing based on JSON passed to objects.
- Worked on canvas to design some nice UI inside the app.



Android Developer

Jlabs

Jun 2015 - May 2016 (1 year)

>> ANDROID Application Developer.<<

- Worked on More than 2 android applications and all are live on Google Play store.
- Experienced in Object Oriented Programming Practices.
- Worked on version control systems SVN, GIT and Web services.
- Proficient in development on development tools Android Studio and Eclipse ADT.
- Worked on various Project Management and reporting tool such as slack.
- Basic knowledge of other mobile technologies PhoneGap.
- Good Knowledge of Layout UI/UX designs of Android.

Education



Amity School of Engineering and Technology

Bachelor of Technology (B.Tech.), Computer Science 2012 - 2016



kalka public school

High School, Computer Science 2008 - 2011

Skills

Android Development • iOS Development • MongoDB • Flask • Docker Products • Strategic Planning Keras

Honors & Awards



Completed LaTeX Training, Certified from IIT Bombay. - IIT Bombay

PRADEEP KUMAR KUSHWAHA has successfully completed LaTeX test organized at Amity School Of Engineering And Technology.